<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text" xml:lang="en">Posts Tagged “DNS” – Development, design, and more by David Ensinger</title><link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://davidensinger.com/tag/dns/atom.xml"/><link href="http://davidensinger.com/"/><id>http://davidensinger.com/</id><updated>2014-01-07T15:19:46Z</updated><author><name>David Ensinger</name><email>hello@davidensinger.com</email></author><rights type="text">Copyright © 2014 David Ensinger. All rights reserved.</rights><entry><title type="text">Setting the DNS for GitHub Pages on Namecheap</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://davidensinger.com/2013/03/setting-the-dns-for-github-pages-on-namecheap/"/><id>http://davidensinger.com/2013/03/setting-the-dns-for-github-pages-on-namecheap</id><published>2013-03-27T16:05:00Z</published><updated>2013-03-27T16:05:00Z</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>After pushing my site to <strong>GitHub</strong> and verifying that it worked at <a href="http://davidensinger.github.io/">davidensinger.github.io</a>, I then went to set up my custom domain name. The <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-pages">documentation</a> provided by GitHub is clear on the subject, but I still managed to forget about my subdomains. For more than eight hours, anyone who attempted to visit <a href="http://davidensinger.com/">davidensinger.com</a> was served with a 404, which is <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidEnsinger/status/316642135216619522">rather embarrassing</a> for one who makes a living as a developer.</p>

<p>In the interest of helping others avoid the mistakes I made, here’s a guide to setting up the DNS for GitHub pages on <a href="http://www.namecheap.com/?aff=32887">Namecheap</a>, my registrar of choice.</p>

<div class="yellow-box">
  <p><strong>Please Note:</strong> This guide has been updated on January 7th, 2014 with new settings to support <a href="https://github.com/blog/1715-faster-more-awesome-github-pages">Faster, More Awesome GitHub Pages</a>.</p>
</div>




<div class="red-box">
  <p><strong>Please Note:</strong> This guide assumes that you’re using an APEX top-level domain (TLD).</p>
</div>


<h2>Add a CNAME File to your Repo</h2>

<p>Create a new file and put your domain name in it. Save it as CNAME.</p>

<pre><code>yourtlddomainname.com
</code></pre>

<h2>Find your Host Records</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/img/posts/2013-03-27-namecheap-all-host-records.png" alt="Image of All Host Records" class="media-right img-border" /></p>

<p>Log into your Namecheap account, select the appropriate domain name, and then go to <strong>All Host Records</strong>.</p>

<h2>Set up the DNS</h2>

<ol>
<li>Set the <strong>@</strong> (used to denote the domain name for which you’re configuring the DNS) <strong>IP Address/URL</strong> to <code>username.github.io</code> and the <strong>Record Type</strong> to <code>CNAME (Alias)</code> with a <strong>TTL</strong> (an acronym for <strong>Time To Live</strong> that refers to the capability of the DNS servers to cache DNS records) of <code>1800</code>.</li>
<li>Set the <strong>www</strong> (the subdomain www) <strong>IP Address/URL</strong> to <code>username.github.io</code> and the <strong>Record Type</strong> to <code>CNAME (Alias)</code> with a <strong>TTL</strong> of <code>1800</code>.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="/assets/img/posts/2014-01-07-namecheap-dns-settings.png" alt="Image of DNS settings" class="media-center img-border" /></p>

<p>Save and then you’re all set! Please note, however that it may take some time for the changes to the DNS to propagate.</p>

<div class="gray-box">
  <p><strong>More Info:</strong> Google has a pretty good <a href="http://support.google.com/a/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=48090">Basic Guide to DNS</a>.</p>
</div>

 ]]></content></entry></feed>